<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>JenkinsDev - General</title><link href="https://jenkinsdev.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://jenkinsdev.github.io/feeds/general.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://jenkinsdev.github.io/</id><updated>2019-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Hello, World!</title><link href="https://jenkinsdev.github.io/blog/2019/hello-world/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>David Jenkins</name></author><id>tag:jenkinsdev.github.io,2019-04-26:/blog/2019/hello-world/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This isn't your usual 'Hello, World' tutorial. This is my personal
introduction to you, the reader.  Find out a little about me, what I do,
and what this &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; is going to be about.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h5&gt;Come One, Come All&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to welcome you &amp;ndash; the reader &amp;ndash; to my blog.  This
is going to be the breeding ground for practically anything, but with
a slight focus on programming related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;A Bit About Me&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is David Jenkins and I currently work over at &lt;a href="https://boldmediagroup.com"&gt;Bold Media Group&lt;/a&gt;.
To sum it up, we do lead generation and aggregation for various insurance
companies. I won't focus too much on what we do, but all
of the information is available through that link!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I'm not working on projects or attempting to keep up with
the latest programmming news and trends you can find me doing various
activities with the family, gaming, or trying to excel myself in some form.
Currently, my main focus is relearning and deepening my understanding of
German.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;How It Was Built&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;The Back-End&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is generated using the lovely &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; static
site generator. Along with it, I make use of &lt;a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;
to write all of the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does make use of a small plugin I wrote back when I originally published
the site in 2014. The plugin does some really basic math to figure out what the read time
is for the average reader. You can check it out over on Github, it's called
&lt;a href="https://github.com/JenkinsDev/pelican-readtime"&gt;pelican-readtime&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, that's about it... Simple is nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;The Front-End&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TODO: Rewrite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sums it up, haha! I'll rewrite this section once I finish rewiring how the front-end
assets are compiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well guys I think that's all I am going to cover in this here "Hello, World!"
tutorial.. I mean introduction.  I am hoping to make this site a
useful resource for all. If you have any questions then just leave
it down below in the comments section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auf Wiedersehen!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="greeting"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="javascript"></category></entry></feed>